Hi so what is green tea?
Green tea, you need to keep in mind, the best ones come from China and Japan.
Green tea also is not fermented, is a term that's used a lot.
It is not also oxidized either.
Once you've picked green tea, what's usually done it's taken automatically into heat.
In Japan they would steam it, in China they would pan fire it and put it into a big wok and add heat to it to stop the tea leaves from withering.
This process keeps green tea, green.
The brew will have a light gold to a green tint.
The Japanese tea you will see a darker emerald type of green.
And in this regard, green tea has a lot of antioxidants that's not present in other teas such as Oolong or black.
In addition green tea has moderate amount of caffeine, because it's still processed a little bit.
The pan firing is done to keep the tea leaves green.
After that they would take it off the wok or the steamer and let the leaves dry on their own.
But in Chinese version, they would roll into various shapes and sizes and such.